Steven Schaab

schaab.steven@gmail.com | 773.656.9747 | Chicago, IL

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/stevenschaab/ | Github: https://github.com/raygun2thehead

Portfolio: https://raygun2thehead.github.io/Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in the Hospitality/Food and Beverage industry. Capable of working under high pressure, adapting quickly and learning on a constant basis. In a past life, worked as a bartender at many great places, including Michelin-Starred restaurants. Also played large roles in the start of 2 well-known Chicago breweries.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PureCSS, Javascript/ES6, JQuery, AJAX

Backend: Nodejs, Express, Handlebars, MySql/Sequelize, MongoDB

Projects

Picniq | Picniq Repo | Picniq Deployed

- Plan a picnic based on either your current location or use an address of your choosing.
- Utilizes geolocation and Foursquare to locate parks and restaurants that are in close proximity to plan a picnic. Responsible for the responsive framework and displaying results to the client side.
- Tools/Languages: FourSquare, OpenCage Geocoder, PureCSS, Bootstrap, GoogleFonts

Plant Parenthood | PlantParenthood Repo | PlantParenthood Deployed

- An app for both current and prospective plant owners to find new plants that fit their lifestyle.
- Allows users to find appropriate plants based on their lifestyle, along with introducing new plants and allowing
 users to sign up and save their favorites. Responsible for the authentication, setting up Cloudinary,
 Handlebars, and some MySQL.
- Tools/Languages: Node.js, Express, Passport, MySQL, Sequelize, Cloudinary, Materialize, Flex-Box, and Handlebars.

Work Experience

Lakeshore Sport and Fitness

Lead Bartender/Beverage Director

June 2019 - March 2020

Chicago, IL

- Revamped cocktail program, taking on a more seasonal and menu inspired concept
- Organized private members parties to run smoothly and more cost-efficient

Old Irving Brewing

Glorified Janitor

August 2016 - November 2018

Chicago, IL

- Conspired on beer focused cocktail menu
- Assisted in brewing test-batches and on the full scale when time permitted

Marz Community Brewing

Lead Bartender/R&D Brewer

July 2014 - September 2016

Chicago, IL

- Wore at least 10 hats. Everyone did to create this
- Spread myself between brewing, cellaring, packaging, pasteurizing, traveling for events, and lots of cleaning
 December 2012 June 2014

Lead Bartender Chicago, IL

Created outside the box cocktails that were course appropriate as well as striking to the senses

Education

Northwestern School of Professional Studies - Chicago, IL

December 2020

Full Stack Coding Certificate

Merrillville High School - Merrillville, IN

Diploma

MOTO